so let's look at the solution to our
move z move n quiz we have this code
and we want to do if conversion of it so
that we get a branch-free code that does
the same work
if conversion amounts to doing the work
of both parts both the not taken and the
taken path
and then selecting between the two and
correcting the results so that only one
of them
is active
so what we have done is these two
instructions are already doing the work
of the
not taken path
it's just that instead of in r2 which
would permanently modify r2 we're
putting the result in r4
and here
the taken
path r3 and 1 are added then we put
result in r5 instead of r3 so what now
needs to happen
is
if this was the correct path to take
then r2 should get the result of r4
otherwise r3 should get the result from
r5
this is a branch on equal
0 r1
so
if r1 is not equal 0
meaning move n
on r1 used as a condition
we're gonna be moving r4
into
r2
if the branch is branching then r1 is
zero
and in that case we want to be moving r5
into r3
and this is our if converted code that
has four instructions worth of work but
no branches in them in contrast the
original code has
three instructions worth of work in this
path
and two instructions worth of work in
this path but it has this branch that
might be difficult to predict